clinicalgeriatrics.com 2019-06-04

# Privacy Policy | HMP

#### PRIVACY STATEMENT

Effective Date: May 22, 2018

This privacy policy describes how HMP Communications (HMP), the North American Center for Continuing Medical Education (NACCME), and Imedex (collectively referred to herein as “HMP,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) collects, uses, discloses and stores the information of those who provide us with their contact information while using our websites, products, events, or services (“Services”). This policy describes the ways that information about our publication subscribers, online and digital media product users, and event registrants (“you” or “Users”) is collected, how that information might be shared, and how Users can request changes to the way their personal information is used or shared. This policy applies to all visitors of HMP and related affiliates’ websites, and covers the products and services for all HMP brands, including but not limited to: journals, national meetings/trade shows, regional meetings, webinars, e-newsletters, microsites, books, videos, blogs, digital networks, social media, etc.

#### INFORMATION WE COLLECT

##### Personal Information

“Personal Information” is information that alone or in combination with other information can be used to identify you, such as your full name, email address, postal address, telephone number, National Provider Identifier (NPI) number and fax number, demographics pertaining to your trade or profession, association membership information and payment information.

We collect, retain and process Personal Information about Users in order to provide our Services and for the other purposes described in this Privacy Policy. We collect Personal Information when you:

  * Register for an account on one of our websites, media products or mobile applications;
  * Register to attend one of our conventions, conferences, webcasts, trade shows, or similar online or in-person events;
  * Subscribe to our publications, magazines (either directly or through a third party (such as a subscription agency);
  * Subscribe to our email newsletters or promotions;
  * Participate in surveys;
  * Apply for job positions on our websites; and
  * Otherwise communicate with us or interact with our websites.

In some cases, you will provide information to us to fully utilize our Services. In other cases, information about you or your activities on our Services may be automatically collected, as further described below.

We also may receive information about you from other sources and add it to the information you have provided to us. For example, we may collect association membership data directly from the organization to which you belong.

The Services may provide discussion forums, discussions or other ways to publicly interact with other Users. HMP encourages Users not to post sensitive personal information in such forums, discussions or other areas. Such information will be accessible to other Users and individuals. HMP and its subsidiaries are not responsible for the information you volunteer about yourself in discussions on our forums or other publicly accessible interactions, or the information that you choose to provide to sponsors or exhibitors during in-person events (i.e., allowing vendors to scan your registration badge in the trade show exhibit hall) or by opting-in to receive company information during a sponsored webinar.

#### Other Information; Cookies

We use cookies (small data files stored on your computer by your web browser upon visiting a website), web beacons, and similar technologies to operate our services efficiently and as intended. A cookie is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the website again, the cookie allows that site to recognize your browser. Cookies may store unique identifiers, user preferences and other information. Through such technologies, we gather information about you, such as your browser type, operating system, IP address, mobile device identification number, the sites visited before and after our Site, and about your interactions with our services, such as the time and date when you viewed a page, which advertisements you have clicked on, and whether you filled out an online form.

We use information gathered through these tools to improve the way our Sites work, for example by employing third-party analytics tools which aggregate anonymous user information to help us better design our sites and enhance the functionality of our services for example, by remembering preferences or other choices that you make - such as user names, language preferences, and the like – we can better understand how you use our site(s) over time. In short, these tools allow us to provide you with a better, more relevant online experience. We may also work with third-party advertising companies to suggest advertisements from the services or on third-party sites based on your preferences.

You may set your browser to block all cookies, including HMP and its subsidiaries while using our services, but doing so will prevent some aspects of our services to not function properly). You may also set your browser to block third-party cookies and allow first-party cookies, which would allow us (but not third parties) to collect such information while you are on our sites. In addition, some browsers may allow you to block certain web beacons and similar tracking codes. Please refer to your browser’s documentation if you wish to block some or all cookies, web beacons, and/or similar tools. To find out more about cookies, including how to manage and delete cookies, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.

#### Third Party Cookies and Tracking Technologies

Like many other organizations, we may use outside marketing companies to place and monitor advertisements or links on our websites. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (links clinked on during a visit, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked on or scrolled over) and personally identifiable information (e.g., NPI number) during your visits to our websites in order to provide advertisements about products and services likely to be of interest to you.

Certain third parties may also employ cookies, web beacons, and/or similar technologies on our Services. Information collected through such third-party tools is gathered directly by such third party, not by HMP or its subsidiaries, and is subject to such third party's applicable privacy policy. Neither HMP nor its subsidiaries has any control over such third-party tools. These third parties include, but are not limited to, analytics partners who help us better understand how our users are interacting with our Services and advertising, providers of widgets and other third-party applications that may appear in our Services, ad servers, ad networks, ad agencies, and advertisers. As noted above, you may set your browser to block third-party cookies.

#### DMD HEALTHCARE COMMUNICATIONS NETWORK℠ PRIVACY STATEMENT

This digital service participates in the DMD Healthcare Communication Network℠ (the "Network"), and as such has implemented various technologies for universal registration/login among all Network member websites. These technologies are managed by DMD Marketing Corp. ("DMD"), and may involve the collection, receipt, and sharing of information with DMD, its clients and other Network members. If you would like to understand how this digital service’s participation in the Network affects your privacy, please click here: http://usersupport.dmdconnects.com/PrivacyPolicy.htm. Please note that the Network registration/login system may be different from the registration/login used by this digital service for other products and services. HMP does not control DMD’s privacy practices. Any information you share while using DMD’s Network technologies are subject to the DMD privacy policy linked above and not this privacy policy.

#### HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We may use your information for the following purposes:

  * to provide the Services to you and improve the Services;
  * to operate, improve, and personalize the products and services we offer, and to give each user a more consistent and personalized experience when interacting with us;
  * to provide you with information about products and services that we think may be of interest to you;
  * for customer service, security, to detect fraud or illegal activities, and for archival and backup purposes in connection with the provision of the Services;
  * to send you account notices, including subscription renewals or registration confirmation, and to provide you with information about products or services you have ordered or which may be of interest to you;
  * for research and analysis purposes;
  * to communicate with users; and
  * to enforce our Terms of Use or other applicable policies.

We may also use your Personal Information to ask for input about our services, events, or products or provide you with additional information about the sites.

We may also, consistent with applicable law, send you e-newsletters with targeted, relevant content. Each e-newsletter will provide you with an opportunity to unsubscribe from that particular e-newsletter. Unsubscribing from one newsletter will not affect delivery of other newsletters or services.

In some cases, consistent with applicable law, we may send you relevant offers from third party businesses or organizations. Many of our customers appreciate receiving these offers because they relate to their business or occupation. However, you will always be able to opt-out of receiving future third party offers.

All promotional and research email messages you receive from us will include an option to opt-out of future email communications from that particular HMP subsidiary or brand.

#### HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES

We may provide your information to our clients as well as those acting as our agents in providing our products and services, including third-party companies we have employed to provide us with specialized services, including customer service, subscription fulfillment, research, statistical analysis, list cleansing, information verification, postal mailings, email and fax deployment, telemarketing, and other information services. In compliance with privacy laws, we also provide our opt-out lists to those third-party companies so that they can be suppressed from the communications those companies send on HMP’ companies behalf.

From time to time our advertisers, sponsors, or exhibitors may wish to receive information detailing User engagement with content, or contact our subscribers and customers who may have indicated an interest in the products, services or events for which the advertiser, sponsor, or exhibitor is associated. If you register for products or services offered by such sponsors or third parties, or for events sponsored in whole or in part by a third party, or otherwise opt-in to permit us to share your personally identifiable information, then you may receive communications, consistent with applicable law, directly from such third parties. If you provide information on a co-branded site or while using a co-branded service, you grant us permission to share the information you have provided with that service or site partner. Their use of your information is subject to their privacy policies and we urge you to read those policies and be aware of their privacy practices before registering.

Should you attend one of our sponsored events, we may provide the Personal Information you provide to us to vendors also attending the event. We will only provide this information to the vendor for a specific use and purpose, but do not warrant that the vendor will keep the same information confidential or private. In addition, we may share your contact information with sponsors who appear in a particular e-newsletter of ours if you click on their link in the e-newsletter, and they may, consistent with applicable law, contact you regarding their products and services.

We may transfer information, including your personal information, in connection with a merger, sale, acquisition or other change of ownership or control by or of us or any affiliated company (in each case whether in whole or in part).

#### INFORMATION TRANSFER

By using the Services, you will transfer data to the United States.

#### HOW WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SECURE

We use reasonable precautions, including appropriate technical, administrative, and physical procedures, designed to protect Personal Information from loss, misuse, or alteration. When we contract with other companies to provide us with services, we will require them to also use reasonable safeguards to protect such Personal Information. However, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for the actions of these parties. Due to the design of the Internet and other factors outside our control, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third parties.

#### CHILDREN'S PRIVACY

The sites are not intended for use by children, especially those under the age of 16. No one under the age of 16 should provide any personal information or participate in any forums, chats, or online discussions. Minors under the age of 18 are prohibited from making purchases, including subscriptions, on our sites. Please discourage your children from providing any personal information about themselves to anyone in any public discussion areas.

#### do not track

The Service does not support Do Not Track at this time. Do Not Track is a privacy preference that you can set in your web browser to indicate that you do not want certain information about your webpage visits collected across websites when you have not interacted with that service on the page. For all the details, including how to turn on Do Not Track, visit www.donottrack.us.

#### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. When we do, we will also revise the “last updated” date below. For changes to this Privacy Policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of your personal information, we will attempt to notify you by email of the change. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time to stay informed about how we are protecting the personal information we collect. If you continue to use our site or services after we have attempted to contact you about material changes to the Privacy Policy, we will assume that you agree to the changes

If you wish to update your print magazine subscription contact information, please go to the magazine's website home page. To access, correct, or ask us to restrict our processing of the Personal Information we have collected about you, or if you wish to opt-out of receiving email, faxes, or phone calls from any HMP brand, please send an email to: dataprivacy@hmpglobal.com or contact us at:

HMP Privacy  
70 E. Swedesford Road  
Suite 100  
Malvern, PA 19355  
Phone: 610.560.0500

We store your Personal Information until you request that we no longer do so or consistent with our internal document retention policies. To ask us to delete and no longer store your Personal Information, please contact us at the addresses provided above.

#### Special notice to California residents

Under California Law SB 27, California residents have the right to receive, once a year, information about third parties with whom we have shared information about you or your family for their marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, and a description of the categories of personal information shared.  To make such a request, please send an email to dataprivacy@hmpglobal.com and please include the phrase “California Privacy Request” in the subject line, and provide us with your name. address and email address.  We will respond to you within-thirty days of receiving such a request.

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION FOR EU RESIDENTS

HMP is the controller of the personal data you submit through the Services. If you are using the Services from the European Union, we will only transfer your Personal Information to the United States through the use of appropriate safeguards such as standard contractual clauses adopted by the European Commission or with your consent. If the transfer of your Personal Information or processing of your Personal Information is based on your consent, you may contact us at [dataprivacy@hmpglobal.com](mailto:dataprivacy@hmpglobal.com) to withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent we will not be able to provide you with access to the Services.

We process personal data as necessary to pursue our legitimate interest of providing the Services to you, marketing products and services to you and to fulfill our contractual obligations to you. You have the right to access your personal data, correct inaccuracies in your personal data, request the erasure of your personal data and restrict the processing of your personal data. For more information about how you can access, rectify and erase your personal data, please see the Section of this Privacy Policy entitled, “Your Rights Over Your Information” above. In addition, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory data protection authority.
